<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>th3hat3d&#39;s bookworm blog!</title>
    <link>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on th3hat3d&#39;s bookworm blog!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <copyright>© th3hat3d</copyright>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - The House on Mango Street</title>
      <link>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/book-review-the-house-on-mango-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 19:13:14 -0500</pubDate>

      <guid>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/book-review-the-house-on-mango-street/</guid>
      <description>Prelude   Hello again, bookworms! I decided to take a detour into the coming-of-age genre for this one, specifically The House on Mango Street by Sandra Cisneros. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot packed into the smattering of vignettes that this book is, so I won&amp;rsquo;t stretch this intro any longer. This is a review with spoilers, so be warned. Diving into this classic starts&amp;hellip; now.
Plot   I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make it short, because it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;d call an insane plot, but a very meaningful one.</description>
      <content>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prelude&#34;&gt;
  Prelude
  &lt;a href=&#34;#prelude&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello again, bookworms! I decided to take a detour into the coming-of-age genre for this one, specifically &lt;em&gt;The House on Mango Street&lt;/em&gt; by Sandra Cisneros. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot packed into the smattering of vignettes that this book is, so I won&amp;rsquo;t stretch this intro any longer. This is a review with spoilers, so be warned. Diving into this classic starts&amp;hellip; now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;
  Plot
  &lt;a href=&#34;#plot&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make it short, because it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;d call an insane plot, but a very meaningful one. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the breakdown to my overall thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with a tiny red house on Mango Street, with the girl Esperanza being there after having moved&amp;hellip; several times. Followed by small vignettes about various micro-aspects of her family life, such as her name, hair of her family members, how she feels about her little sister Nenny, or her friend for a week Cathy (also the queen of cats). Importantly, Esperanza and her sisters receive a bag of shoes, which includes multiple pairs of high heels. Starting with Rachel, they come to enjoy the feeling of womanhood and anticipate the attention from boys. But when a drunk man tries to kiss Rachel, they immediately notice the danger of their attention and put the shoes away. At a church, Esperanza dances only in her ordinary shoes with her uncle, but yet focuses on the stare of a boy who watched her dance. And at work, she is forcibly kissed by a man who lures her with a conversation. Her aunt who listens to her poetry and stories despite slowly dying and becoming blind dies while she and her friends insensitively imitate her. She then meets Ruthie, a woman with potential outside of Mango Street who nonetheless stays there, trapped by her husband despite her desire to leave. Esperanza finds solace in trees just like her, who grew amongst concrete and reach as high as they can while distancing herself from her Spanish heritage. Majorly, she proceeds to meet a beautiful girl named Sally who is abused and locked at home by her father because of her beauty. Her propensity to be with other boys leads her to ditch Esperanza with a boy, where she proceeds to be raped by a group of men, misled by the glamorized images of sex that Sally filled her with. Finally, the aunts of Lucy and Rachel tell her fortune, informing her that Mango Street will always be part of her and that she will come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, Esperanza plans to come back for the ones that have no way out of Mango Street; the ones she leaves behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall-thoughts&#34;&gt;
  Overall Thoughts
  &lt;a href=&#34;#overall-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I even get to the themes and characters of the novel, I&amp;rsquo;d first like to praise the structure of the book itself. I love books with a non-linear structure like the one in Mango Street, since it makes the overall plot and reading experience more interesting. Here, though, it&amp;rsquo;s many disconnected scenes, and you don&amp;rsquo;t know when they are. Yet, these mini-stories all tie together, but not into one cohesive and complete puzzle. It&amp;rsquo;s more like many different puzzles that share common themes and elements. The reader&amp;rsquo;s job is to find the threads connecting these puzzles, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite elements of the novel. The following three puzzles are my favorites, but there are many more, so please do a reread if you’ve already read it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;discovery-of-identity&#34;&gt;
  Discovery of Identity
  &lt;a href=&#34;#discovery-of-identity&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I love about how Esperanza discovers her identity is that she doesn&amp;rsquo;t proceed by her discovering a new part of herself (although she does do so), but by shifting the way she thinks about her identity and setting. Instead of constantly desiring that Mango Street wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of her, she accepts that it is a part of who she is even after she leaves it. Her working-class background and Chicana heritage will never leave her either, which is what the community of Mango Street is meant to represent. Her discovery of her womanhood is also crafted through her connections with others and not by herself, through characters who face the wrath of patriarchy in their lives and sisters who experiment with what it feels like to transition from girlhood to womanhood. Esperanza does not choose to embrace her femininity, but aims to have more agency and independence in her life, like the men she has seen have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;female-entrapment&#34;&gt;
  Female Entrapment
  &lt;a href=&#34;#female-entrapment&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I love about this book is that female oppression is explored in multiple different ways; it does not just repeat insights of the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sally is beaten and abused by her father, and then proceeds to let herself be taken advantage of by boys when she embraces her female beauty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruthie wanted to pursue greater things than what she is at the present moment, but waits to leave Mango Street until her husband does so due to societal standards, which has not happened yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marin is waiting on the pieces to fall together for her in order to leave Mango Street. It&amp;rsquo;s different than Ruthie&amp;rsquo;s case because patriarchy is internalized within her, squashing any initiative that she may have to seek her own path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rachel embracing her newfound womanhood with the heels in the bag, but is immediately confronted with unwanted attention from other men.
These are just some examples, but the multifaceted look at women’s oppression is great and refreshing to see in a fictional story such as this one. Also, what happens to Esperanza when Sally leaves her alone… I don’t want to say it here, but it was something I wasn’t expecting. Perfect way to capture how sudden and scary assault is for women (the possibility of it too). Thematically, one of my favorite parts of the novel. Chef’s kiss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;belonging&#34;&gt;
  Belonging
  &lt;a href=&#34;#belonging&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example of the lack of this one is Marin, who is waiting for someone or something to come along and carve her path for her. Because she has difficulty with finding belonging and, by extension, her own identity, she needs someone else to bring it to her. Esperanza knows that she belongs outside of Mango Street, but has difficulty realizing that it is part of who she is, even if it might not be the right place for her. It manifests in how she prefers English over Spanish or having her dream home be a polar opposite of her family’s tiny house on Mango Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marin is only capable of hope and longing, while Esperanza has the power to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;long, but that place lies outside of where she currently is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;
  Final Thoughts
  &lt;a href=&#34;#final-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I adore about this book is how much depth and rich character is communicated in just 44 short vignettes, and it’s very realistic. There aren’t an excessive amount of characters, and the ones that are prominent are very well-developed and fleshed out, especially Sally and Esperanza. As people, we don’t see most people that often or ever again, and this book knows that. Therefore, the choice to not develop Marin or Ruthie (for example) is a positive. I could not afford to give this book any less than the 5/5 it deserves as a classic. It’s approachable, but it is not at all a beach read. Give it a standing ovation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play Review - English Made Simple</title>
      <link>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/play-review-english-made-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 22:47:59 -0500</pubDate>

      <guid>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/play-review-english-made-simple/</guid>
      <description>﻿Hello again, bookworms! Today, I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing a one-act play that I quite enjoyed and resonated with; one called English Made Simple. It&amp;rsquo;s part of a larger series of play reviews/analyses from David Ives&#39; beautiful All in the Timing collection, which I was introduced to in my school&amp;rsquo;s theater class. Enjoying them as much as I did, here I am making my first iteration of the series. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!
A Classroom Introduction   As previously mentioned, this play was one I was introduced to in school.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;﻿Hello again, bookworms! Today, I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing a one-act play that I quite enjoyed and resonated with; one called English Made Simple. It&amp;rsquo;s part of a larger series of play reviews/analyses from David Ives&#39; beautiful &lt;em&gt;All in the Timing&lt;/em&gt; collection, which I was introduced to in my school&amp;rsquo;s theater class. Enjoying them as much as I did, here I am making my first iteration of the series. Let&amp;rsquo;s start!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-classroom-introduction&#34;&gt;
  A Classroom Introduction
  &lt;a href=&#34;#a-classroom-introduction&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, this play was one I was introduced to in school. But the class also performed it as well, making the experience for this one even better. I will say for this one, the play being performed definitely brings out the socially comedic elements of it more than just reading it, though that&amp;rsquo;s just me. You&amp;rsquo;ll see what I mean when I get to describing the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3-the-party-section-1-saying-hello&#34;&gt;
  Chapter 3: The Party, Section 1: Saying Hello
  &lt;a href=&#34;#chapter-3-the-party-section-1-saying-hello&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first little section starts with a dig at the idea of first impressions. Apparently, the first three minutes of conversation can determine the results of the relations between two people for the rest of eternity. It sounds a bit ridiculous, which is the entire point; first impressions shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be everything, though they do seem to be in the ensuing conversation. It&amp;rsquo;s awkward as all heck, where both sides are at a complete loss for what to say. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s had an experience like that at some point, and I love how Ives relates to the reader in that way with the most painfully awkward party scenario possible. He&amp;rsquo;s telling us that we&amp;rsquo;re probably not as bad at socializing as we think; at least we haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced something &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; awkward (probably, anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ives next touches on a micro-occurrence that we&amp;rsquo;ve all had, but that&amp;rsquo;s hard to explain. The previous conversation repeats, but with just alien-like beeps and boops; yet, we can still discern the general awkward nature of the conversation. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably been in a public space before, and overhear a conversation but don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what&amp;rsquo;s being said. But Ives gets at the part where we understand the general feeling of the exchange just by how it sounds. To me, a genius and pinpoint usage of the English language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short segment of a guy trying to woo a woman at a party ensues, doing an excellent job of encapsulating the frequency of times which an interaction can be summed up by just two words: &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Goodbye.&amp;rdquo; Brevity of social interactions is real, as if Ives is pulling the reader&amp;rsquo;s ear to call back all those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-2-the-structure-of-english-conversation&#34;&gt;
  Section 2: The Structure of English Conversation
  &lt;a href=&#34;#section-2-the-structure-of-english-conversation&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one focuses on, as the title says, the structure of conversations. Another sentiment beautifully displayed by Ives is how much socializing can feel like a template; an outline where we just fill in the blank. And it does feel that way a lot of the time, in opposition with a no-pressure and free-flowing interaction. We do get to see that next, but with a painful experience attached to it. It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to have a person that you&amp;rsquo;ve had a falling-out with and eventually come across them again, but all there is to talk about is the feel-good times you had; there&amp;rsquo;s nothing new to be had. Sad times for sure, and Ives masterfully portrays that type of encounter so well that it&amp;rsquo;s a better depiction than even a mind can come up with. Mixing it with the free-flowing and template-free social interaction theme is the cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-3-simultaneous-translation&#34;&gt;
  Section 3: Simultaneous Translation
  &lt;a href=&#34;#section-3-simultaneous-translation&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could give a one sentence summary of this part, it would be this: two people trying to roast each other in the most professional way possible. Ives manifests the feeling of knowing exactly what someone means despite the person not telling you, especially when they hate you. Of course, he equally portrays the other side of the coin; AKA, where you have a hard time figuring out other people&amp;rsquo;s intentions. At the same time, it is an expression of the pain we feel when we can&amp;rsquo;t truly express our thoughts. Always having to convey our thoughts in such a sanitized way is an agony all people have to deal with, and the comedic way Ives weaves this meaning with an exercise in social understanding can&amp;rsquo;t be understated. Only problem is the length, since it had the potential to be so much more if it was a longer section. But on its own merit, the praise still stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-7-fill-in-the-blank&#34;&gt;
  Section 7: Fill In The Blank
  &lt;a href=&#34;#section-7-fill-in-the-blank&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one takes the theme of template-like social interactions from Section 2, but twists it in a completely new direction and meaning. It&amp;rsquo;s about the déjà-vu of having had essentially the same conversation in the past; the names and places change, but it&amp;rsquo;s the same feeling and result at the end. But what truly differentiates Section 7 from Section 2 is how it implies the idea of an mutual comprehension between two individuals, in terms of having had the same social experience with another person. Exactly captures that &amp;ldquo;me too!&amp;rdquo; experiential moment, which Ives perfectly interleaves with déjà-vu. A genius theme double entendre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-26-the-conditional-tense&#34;&gt;
  Section 26: The Conditional Tense
  &lt;a href=&#34;#section-26-the-conditional-tense&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately recycling the tease on first impressions from the first section, I love the idea of exploring the other side of it: a great first impression. And then proceeds to smoothly parody the ever-expanding mental tree we make of our potential relationship to another person, only to come back to reality near the end. Ives makes us take a look at ourselves here; to not look so much at the should, would, and could of our daily interactions. But instead, we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; (see what I did there?) also focus on reality and go with the flow of the situation we&amp;rsquo;re in. It&amp;rsquo;s just as much a dream as it is a reality, and Ives&#39; execution in communicating that is a perfect 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;section-78-saying-goodbye&#34;&gt;
  Section 78: Saying Goodbye
  &lt;a href=&#34;#section-78-saying-goodbye&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I hate how short this one is, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious what it stands for. Ives takes the &amp;ldquo;just act normal&amp;rdquo; we tell ourselves when nervous and turns it into an actual narrator who is essentially giving the person save states for their social impression. I especially admire how Ives implicitly conveys the inner desperation we feel when trying to act normal, and pat ourselves on the back when we give up and act raw. It may not have been perfect, but we still deserve an A+ for effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;
  Conclusion
  &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely loved these mini parodies of common occurrences and epiphanies of social life, with the realistic nature of each situation making it even more relatable to the reader (it is a &lt;strong&gt;play&lt;/strong&gt; after all). My only issues with English Made Simple are that some sections are too short and feel too forced-in for the sake of the performance (Section 78 in particular). I&amp;rsquo;d give it a 4.7/5, with micro-points taken off for the aforementioned reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ceHtXHaovc8&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of the play being performed, by the way, which definitely encapsulates the interpersonal parts of the play better than words can.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - Unhinged</title>
      <link>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/book-review-unhinged/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 18:26:59 -0500</pubDate>

      <guid>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/posts/book-review-unhinged/</guid>
      <description>Hello, fellow bookworms! This is my first site on this bookish blog of mine, and what better way to start it off than with a book review? But not just any old book. It’s a romance about a girl and… a door. Yeah, it’s weird. There are spoilers in this review, but the book itself isn’t that long (you should read it if you can bear).
Preamble   I heard about this book through this video while scouring BookTube.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello, fellow bookworms! This is my first site on this bookish blog of mine, and what better way to start it off than with a book review? But not just any old book. It’s a romance about a girl and… a door. Yeah, it’s weird. There are spoilers in this review, but the book itself isn’t that long (you should read it if you can bear).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preamble&#34;&gt;
  Preamble
  &lt;a href=&#34;#preamble&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about this book through this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/szFXk8yLvK4?si=QFe8QHZ04AmLt1lH&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; while scouring BookTube. Before even reading it, I had to laugh at the basic premise. A woman falling in love with a door has got to be one of the most unconventional plot lines I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard about. But I wanted to know what it was all about (so of course, I read it), and was both amused and bewildered by the end. Felt like a fever dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-plot&#34;&gt;
  The Plot
  &lt;a href=&#34;#the-plot&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you go into this one knowing the overarching A and B of the book (the aforementioned door and woman love story). What I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect, though, was the surprising amount of twists and turns. It starts from the door&amp;rsquo;s POV, who we learn is sentient, describing the little things that make him love Tana (the girl) as much as he does. From the way she puts her fingers on his knob to the softness of the skin near his peephole, he&amp;rsquo;s very attuned to the sensory details of Tana. Makes sense, considering he can&amp;rsquo;t talk to her. At this point, I thought it would be just a fast-paced love story between these two; there was the question of how the door would deal with it being, you know, a &lt;em&gt;door&lt;/em&gt;. That didn&amp;rsquo;t last long, though, because we learn that Tana&amp;rsquo;s landlord Randall wants to kill her. There was another girl that he took into the woods who was never seen again, and the door receives a message from Zeus himself that this is the case. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a propensity for books with some godly intervention (Percy Jackson, anyone?), so this was a bias point for me. I loved how the door was able to literally &lt;strong&gt;enter Tana&amp;rsquo;s dreams&lt;/strong&gt; as a human male and inform her about the evil nature of her landlord, but it felt too keyholed (get it, &lt;em&gt;door&lt;/em&gt;? Haha) and forced into the story; there was no rhyme or reason to have this plot device be used and it would&amp;rsquo;ve been better to have this be an established superpower of the door or something that made sense in accordance with the current plot. A knob twisting morse code SOS signal would&amp;rsquo;ve been great to see, but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the dream, the meat and potatoes of the story begins: the sex. It&amp;rsquo;s not apparent in how Tana develops her sexual desire for the door, and is another empty plot hole that I&amp;rsquo;d love to see filled in (or not, I can imagine how cringe Tana&amp;rsquo;s spiral into insanity is). I&amp;rsquo;m for sure not writing it, though. Point is, Tana now has a door kink and wants some knob action (if you know what I mean). Girl literally teases him sexually by rubbing her thumb on his knob (supposed to be his cock, getting him riled up for what happens next. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details, but let&amp;rsquo;s just say they have intercourse. Leaving it at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The events that follow are packed into the final few chapters, which I personally don’t approve of since I would’ve appreciated a slower descent after the climax (but it’s supposed to be fast-paced, so who am I to judge?) It’s absolutely insane, so bear with me. Tana is about to drink some orange juice laced with drugs by her evil landlord, and the door suddenly turns into a human through some mysterious method. Again with the unestablished magical powers (hilarious though), but I’ll fill that in with my own lore later. Now-human door knocks the OJ out of her hands, saving her life while she is still startled from his appearance. At this point, she realized that the man (whose name is Drys) who just saved her was the door she had sex with. Randall then comes in armed with a gun, ready to kill Tana if the medicine hadn’t already brought her down. Drys takes the gunshot for Tana and is transformed back into a door, albeit with a hole in the center of it. While replacing the door due to damage, Tana prays to Hera to get Drys back and has sex with the door again per her command. Indeed he turns back into a human, with the stipulation that they have to engage in intercourse every 30 days, since he will turn back into a door upon full moons (literal doorwolf). The story ends there, but with some satisfying closure. Tana and Drys are made for each other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall-thoughts&#34;&gt;
  Overall Thoughts
  &lt;a href=&#34;#overall-thoughts&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the instant I closed my e-book, I was thinking: what in the living heck did I just read? Not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand what I read, but I found the story line to be so wacky and embarrassing that it was actually a joy to look back on. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot packed into the short length of this one, such as femdom (the door loves to be submissive to Tana) and Greek mythology. My main gripe with the book was the Swiss-cheese worth of plot holes, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting much from a fan-fiction novel about a door and woman falling in love anyway. Also, there&amp;rsquo;s barely any character development except for Drys adapting to being human; I didn&amp;rsquo;t find this too much of a downside, though. It was great at holding my attention though, as it definitely hooks you in and leaves you hanging with every chapter. Or maybe it all goes back to the book&amp;rsquo;s weird premise. Definitely a book for when you want a quick laugh or some spicy kink in your romance, but the quality of the writing could&amp;rsquo;ve been better. 3/5 for this one, if I&amp;rsquo;m being generous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;
  Highlights
  &lt;a href=&#34;#highlights&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading, I just had to annotate some parts of it due to the sheer absurdity of it all. Here are the quotes I highlighted along with my associated comment. Have fun with these!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a door, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know when I fell in love with Tana, only that I most assuredly was.&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 1)
What made you love her so much? How fulfilling was that relationship WHEN YOU ARE LITERALLY A DOOR&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have no name but your, Tana. I am your faithful guardian and protector, nothing more, nothing less. I am your door, and I love you.&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 5)
Assert your door dominance, strange door man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I&amp;rsquo;m even considering this. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotta be out of my fucking mind.&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 6)
Welp. Here she goes. But why? Where is this coming from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;her thumb slipping over my raised lock ridge through the thin barrier of the cloth, almost teasingly&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 7)
Gee, what a detail. How smooth must her her thumb be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The shiny square fluttered to the floor and some sort of long, slippery-looking translucent sock hung in Tana&amp;rsquo;s fingertips.&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 7)
Wow. A condom on a door. Has that sentence even been said before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I really liked it when she bossed me around&amp;rdquo; (Chap. 14)
You could&amp;rsquo;ve just said you loved the femdom, brother. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to be so cryptic about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;
  Ending Off
  &lt;a href=&#34;#ending-off&#34; class=&#34;hanchor&#34; ariaLabel=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading my first of many book reviews to come! This was a weird first book to review, but I wanted to have it that way. More &lt;em&gt;conventional&lt;/em&gt; books are coming in the future; I needed to get my foot in the door somehow, though. Remember to stay bookish, and I&amp;rsquo;ll see you later!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>

      <guid>https://bookworm.deadandbeef.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Just some nerdy kid from the States. A budding opportunist, I take any opportunity that comes my way. As a lifelong learner, I strive to explore the literary world as I desire and anything else I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. Speaking of which, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some interests of mine, if you would like to know:
 Mathematics Tech Networking Books (ofc) Chess Music (Dubstep and EDM especially) Anything nerdy!  This blog was made as a way for me to write about my bookish hobby and being a bookworm, and share it with other readers and whoever else happens to be interested.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Just some nerdy kid from the States. A budding opportunist, I take any opportunity that comes my way. As a lifelong learner, I strive to explore the literary world as I desire and anything else I&amp;rsquo;m interested in. Speaking of which, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some interests of mine, if you would like to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books (ofc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (Dubstep and EDM especially)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything nerdy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog was made as a way for me to write about my bookish hobby and being a bookworm, and share it with other readers and whoever else happens to be interested. Put simply, it&amp;rsquo;s my personal literary outlet. Enjoy your time here.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to see my other projects or blogs, my GitHub is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/th3hat3d&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
